联邦军队的统领是.
The commander of the Confederate Army was...
李小龙
Bruce Lee.
“李.罗伯特”
"Robert E. Lee."
差一点
Close.
内战于1861年爆发，一直到.
The Civil War started in 1861 and lasted...
很久很久以后
far too long.
“1865”
"1865."
你真是帅呆了
You are so cool.
跟我说话？
You talking to me?
只有我在这
I'm the only one here.
走开，臭小子! 我在看书
Leave me alone. I'm trying to study, scuzzball.
臭小子？
Scuzzball?
对不起，爸爸，还以为是本 我不会当面骂你是臭小子
Sorry, Dad, thought you were Ben. I'd never call you scuzzball to your face.
麦克，你说过会打扫房间的
Mike, you said you were gonna be cleaning up your room.
是的
I did.
干得好
Nice.
-这音乐是否吵了点？ -是很吵
- That music a little loud? - Oh, absolutely.
干嘛？我在看书呢
Dad, what are you doing? I'm trying to study here.
我不是质疑你的学习方法.
Oh, well, I surely don't want to interfere with a study method...
让你徘徊及格边缘的学习方法
that has brought you to the brink of failure this year, Mike.
但考虑到客厅天花板的安全.
But for the sake of the plaster on the living room ceiling...
我希望你温习历史时免受干扰
I'd like you to study for this history test without any loud distractions.
太安静会让我抓狂
I don't know, Dad, all that silence could really throw me off.
就冒险一次吧
Let's risk it.
静静看一个小时书试试
Come on, just you and this book for one solid hour.
什么意思？给压力我拿好成绩？
What's this? Are you pressuring me for a good grade?
不，作为一个务实主义者 我是给压力你及格
No, I'm a realist, Mike. I'm pressuring you for a passing grade.
常年累月啃历史书才67分
Come on, you've been squeaking through American History all year with a 67.
-不好意思
-68 - 68. - Oh, pardon me.
这次考试是进步的大好时机
Come on. Look, with this exam you have a chance to really improve on that.
为什么不提高目标，70!75!
Why don't you aim for the stars? 70. 75!
爸，你以为我不懂历史吗？
Dad, I get the feeling you don't think I know this stuff.
林肯被刺是.
Abraham Lincoln was assassinated...
是真的
True.
圣人曾说过.
Well, a very wise man once said, Mike...
“不懂历史的人注定要重蹈覆辙”
that, "Those who do not know their history are doomed to repeat it."
-你是指暑假补习班？ -正是
- You mean like in summer school? - Exactly.
林肯被刺是在.
Abraham Lincoln was assassinated...
他活着的时候
while he was still alive.
(English Subtitle) Growing.Pains.S01E18 -= Reputation =- Subripped by zerox
杰森
Jason.
瞧
Look.
想不到麦克还在看书
Well, Mike's still studying. What do you know?
看来我说服了他
Looks like I actually got through to him.
肯定是了
Yeah, yeah, that must be it.
也许你启发了他对知识的渴求
You probably got him so fired up he's dizzy with the thirst for knowledge.
听听看
Okay, just listen.
-麦克？ -什么事？
- Mike? - Yeah?
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
怎么了？
Why?
好奇而已，还在看书？
I'm curious. Are you still studying?
[导演：约翰.特莱西] 是的，不可能会不及格
Yeah. There's no way I'm gonna flunk this test.
杰森，有人在模仿麦克的声音
Jason, there's somebody in that room imitating Mike's voice.
妈，一点都不好笑
Oh, very funny, Mom.
麦克，答案是？
Mike, the answer?
快想到了
I'm very close.
快点，我累了
Oh, come on, I'm tired.
我也累啊
Hey, this is no picnic for me either.
说出美国任何一位将军的名字
A General. Just name any American General.
将军.
General...
通用汽车
Motors.
-够了，我睡了 -睡觉？
- That's it. I'm going to bed. - Bed?
生死关头怎么能睡觉？
Come on, how can you think of bed at a time like this?
看你沉醉在自己的无知里真是郁闷
Watching you wallow in your ignorance is too demoralizing.
晚安
Good night.
你成绩那么好，你是怎样学习的？
Okay, well, if you're so good at it, how do you study?
很简单，先预习.
It's very simple. I read the material when it's assigned...
划出重点
I underline the key phrases...
做好笔记，自我测试
I take careful notes, and I quiz myself.
划出重点
Underlining.
-嗨 -嗨，昨晚干什么去了？
- Hi. - Hi, where have you been?
学习到很晚
Oh, I was up late studying.
-你也要测验？ -不
- Do you have a test, too? - No.
麦克能学到她一半就好了
See, Mike could learn something from her.
不可能得
No, he couldn't.
-再见 -再见
- Well, bye. - Bye.
真讨厌饱后剧烈运动
Well, I hate to eat and run.
-煎蛋还没吃完 -我已经很饱了
- Hey, you didn't even finish your eggs. - Well, what I ate was very filling.
别敷衍我，不必找借口
Come on. You don't have to give me that. You don't have to make up a story.
不喜欢吃就说吧
If you didn't like your breakfast, just say so.
-杰森 -我听得下去
- Jason... - I can take it.
-我.. -说吧
- Well, l... - Go ahead, say it.
-太难吃了 -好
- It was yuck. - Okay, then.
这样好多了
That's better.
说笑啦，再见
Just kidding. Bye-bye.
全部都难吃还是煎蛋难吃？
All of it or just the eggs?
这也算煎蛋？
Those were eggs?
给历史学家说声早安吧
Okay, say good morning to God's gift to history.
看来你已经准备好历史大考
Well, you look like a guy who's ready for a big history test.
不是一般的准备好
Ready. I am not just ready, Dad.
这次是万事具备 名字，日期，所有事情
I have got it all: Names, dates, everything.
今天是我麦克.西弗出人头地的大日子
I think today will go down in history as the day Mike Seaver turns a corner.
1986年2月20日
February 20, 1986.
是2月25日
It's February 25.
-爸爸 -本
- Hey, Dad. - Hi, Ben.
这就是早餐？
This is breakfast?
是的
Yes.
那午餐呢？
What's for lunch?
我会给你惊喜
A surprise.
Uh-oh.
我讨厌惊喜
I hate surprises.
爸爸让我吃鞋子了？
Why is Dad feeding me shoes?
本，那是我的袋子
Ben, that's my bag.
-爸爸让你吃鞋子了？ -本，还我，我需要的
- Why is Dad feeding you shoes? - Ben, come on, give it. I need that.
“李.罗伯特”，“史丹沃.杰克森”
"Robert E. Lee, Stonewall Jackson...
“阿波马托克斯法庭”
"Appomattox Court House."
这些是我的朋友，签名留念
Yeah, yeah, they're my buddies. I had them sign them for good luck.
你有个朋友叫“阿波马托克斯法庭”
You know somebody named Appomattox Court House?
对，黑人，棒球队队长
Yeah. A black guy, captain of the basketball team.
空手道，踢到墙壁了
Karate. I just kicked over a brick wall.
我只知道我不知道这个
The one thing I know is that I don't know this.
老兄，你太杞人忧天了
Bone, my man, you worry too much.
还好暑假补习班有你陪
Well, at least I'll have you for company in summer school.
今非昔比，我这次肯定过
No, not this time. I got this thing aced.
你真的去背这些东西了？
You mean to tell me you actually studied this stuff?
邦纳，邦纳，邦纳
Boner, Boner, Boner.
年少无知
So young, so naive.
埃迪，他写了作弊条.
You've got cheat notes. Eddie, he's got...
别那么大声，大家会胡思乱想
Come on, you say that too loud and people are gonna get the wrong idea.
在哪里？
Where are they?
我不知道你们在说什么
Look, I don't know what you guys are talking about.
来，全身搜查我吧
Here, search me. Here you go, full-body strip search.
不了，谢谢
No, thanks.
老师来了!
Teacher! Teacher!
好吧，同学们
All right, people.
我知道大家都吓倒了
I trust you're all sufficiently frightened.
要不然，你真的要吓倒了
If not, you should be.
因为本次测验会占总成绩的四分之一
'Cause this test will count for a quarter of your total grade.
四分之一!昨天不是说25%吗？
A quarter! Only yesterday he said 25%.
多选题
This is multiple choice.
30分钟，改卷后才能放学
You have 30 minutes, and your papers will be graded before you leave.
开始
You may begin.
“内战的最后战役是：A.布尔溪战役”
"The final northern battle of the Civil War was, A: Battle of Bull Run...
“B.盖茨堡战役” “C.网星战役”
"B: Battle of Gettysburg, or C: Battle of the Network Stars."
盖茨堡
Gettysburg.
我真的懂这些题目!
Hey, I actually know this stuff!
考试成绩让人吃惊
Now, some of your test results did surprise me.
例如斯达邦同学回答的.
For instance, it was interesting to learn from Mr. Stabone...
格兰特将军原来姓娄
that General Grant's first name was Lou.
看不下去了!
I can't look, I can't look.
得看下去!
I've gotta look.
67!好棒!
67! All right!
继男孩开始戴耳环后.
In what is perhaps the biggest shock in my teaching career...
本人教书生涯中最大的惊奇是.
since boys started wearing earrings...
本班最高分，94分.
the highest grade in the class, a 94...
获得者是.
was earned by...
麦克.西弗
Mike Seaver.
我是第一名!
I am number one!
-第一名! -第一名!
- Number one! - Number one!
西弗同学，在记者招待会以前.
Mr. Seaver, before we schedule a press conference...
我得问问.
I have to ask...
一个别名叫“刚及格”的同学.
how does a student whose very name has become synonymous...
怎能获得如此好成绩？
with the phrase "D minus", manage such a grade?
我还能怎么说 好成绩要来，谁也拦不住
What can I say, Mr. Dewitt? When you got it, you got it.
现在我知道原因了
And now I see where you got it.
你真的认为我作弊？
Are you actually calling me a cheater?
西弗同学，别想骗老师
Mr. Seaver, don't try to fool Willy Dewitt.
鞋子，立刻拿来
The shoes. Now.
老师.
Mr. Dewitt...
请你的家长，监护人或假释官来开会
Have your parent, guardian, or parole officer call for an appointment.
越快越好
The sooner the better.
他打你了？
He beat you?
不，只是拿走了鞋子
No, he just took my shoes.
-麦克，真臭 -臭气熏天
- Oh, that stinks, Mike. - Yeah, real bad, too.
我最恨的是他以为我作弊
What really bothers me is that this guy thinks I cheated.
竟有这种事？!
Boy, hard to imagine!
他竟然没相信我的话
I mean, he wouldn't even take my word that I didn't.
西弗，真是好样的
Seaver, you really are good.
什么意思？
What's that supposed to mean?
面临历史不及格，甚至退学.
Well, I mean, here you are facing suspension and an F in history...
你还能装无辜
and you're cool enough to play it innocent.
我是无辜的!
Look, I am innocent!
而且动怒了，发狂了
And outrage, too. Outrage is tough.
我只能悄悄发脾气
I can only work up to a small frenzy myself.
我没有作弊!
Look, I did not cheat!
对，甚至没有看过鞋底一次
No, and you didn't look at the answers on your shoes even once.
我没有说笑!
Look, I'm not kidding around!
也许这里有窃听器
You know, maybe he's got the room bugged.
当然了，麦克不会作弊
Of course, Mike, you would never cheat.
我没有作弊，你们说够了没有？
Look, I did not cheat, and I'm tired of you guys saying that I did!
听到没有？
You got it?
本周连续5晚.
Five nights this week...
美国人脍炙人口的故事 将会搬上荧幕
the story that had all America reading, will have all America watching.
18岁，修女
At 18, she was a nun.
21岁，体操运动员，37岁，总统夫人
At 21, an acrobat. At 37, the mistress of a president.
琼.科林是.
Joan Collins is...
老太婆
Old.
-麦克 -嗨
- Hi, Mike. - Hi.
你怎么了？
What's the matter?
你怎么知道我怎么了？
How do you know something's the matter?
因为你没叫我“贱货”，“臭嘴”或“傻蛋”
Because you didn't say, "Hi, Fido," "Hi, Skunk-breath," or "Hi, Nerd-face."
怎么了？
So, what is it?
我恶梦成真了，没有人相信我
Carol, I'm living a nightmare. I mean, nobody believes me.
邦纳，埃迪，切奇，莫里他们都不信我
Not Boner, not Eddie, not Cheech, not Murray.
你在说什么？
What are you talking about?
老师说我历史考试作弊
Mr. Dewitt accused me of cheating on my history exam.
你及格了？
You passed!
是的
Yeah, I passed.
而且我得到了最高分
In fact, I got the highest grade in the class.
你是说你也不相信我
Oh, oh, is this your way of saying you don't believe me either?
-够了 -好吧!
- Stop! - Oh, oh, fine.
不相信罢了，臭嘴!贱货!傻蛋!
Don't believe me, Skunk-breath! Fido! Nerd-face!
爸!妈!看见你们真好
Mom! Dad! How great to see you!
-嗨 -他是在跟我们说话吗？
- Hey. - Is he talking to us?
我信任你们能让我快乐
I mean, just knowing that I can count on you guys makes me feel happy.
这种信任是双向的
Oh, the giddiness is completely mutual, Mike.
谢谢
Hey, you're welcome.
-发烧了？ -妈
- Do you have a fever? - Mom.
麦姬，我说这是不是.
Say, Maggie, you don't suppose this has anything to do...
兴最近的历史考试有关呢？
with his recent history test, do you?
说到这个刚好
You know, I'm darn glad you brought that up, Dad.
我还是先坐下
I'd better sit down.
怎么了？
What happened?
考试本身没什么好说的
Well, there's not too much to be said about the test itself.
还是说说看吧
Say it anyway.
及格了
I passed.
-完全及格了？ -太好了
- Completely? - Yeah.
-麦克，好啊 -恭喜
- Hey, all right, Mike. - Congratulations.
额外的温习果然奏效
I knew that that little extra studying would pay off.
谢谢
Thanks.
不过我有坏消息
But I do have some bad news...
爸，你还是先坐下
and I think you better sit down for this, Dad.
麦克，说吧
Just say what it is, Mike.
我认为你还是先坐下吧
I have a feeling you should sit.
我说出这件事后，你们将会很气愤
Now what I'm about to tell you is going to get both of you quite angry...
甚至会对老师的做法.
and you will be outraged at the shoddy treatment...
感到生气，勃然大怒
I have received from Mr. Dewitt.
不过你要承诺，不能兴冲冲地.
But I want your word that you're not gonna go off half-cocked...
要让他被学校开除
trying to get this guy fired or something.
我承诺不会这样
I promise to be fully-cocked, Mike.
老师指控我.
Now, Mr. Dewitt accused me...
考试作弊
of cheating.
-冷静点! -我很冷静
- Now just calm down! - I'm in control.
我没有作弊
I did not cheat!
老师为什么会这样做？
Now why would Mr. Dewitt think that?
整个下午我也在问自己这个问题
You know, I have been asking myself that same question all afternoon.
那你想到些什么？
Well, what'd you come up with, Mike?
也许他想不到我成绩那么好
I don't know. I guess he didn't expect me to do that well on the test.
好？成绩好？
Well? You did well? He did well.
有多好？
How well?
我很少在意分数
I rarely pay attention to the grades.
-多少分？70？
-75？ - What'd you get? 70? - 75?
-这个..
-80？ - Well... - 80?
-这..
-85？ - See... - 85?
-其实..
-90？ - Actually... - 90?
-4 -94!
- Four. - 94!
麦克.西弗，我为你感到羞耻!
Why, Michael Seaver, I'm ashamed of you!
-你怎么能作弊! -我没有作弊!
- How could you cheat? - I did not cheat.
满分是100分的那种94？
Is this 94 out of 100?
我发誓我没有作弊
I swear to you I did not cheat.
否则五雷轰顶
Dad, I give you my word of honor.
我相信你
Well, I believe you.
-是吗？ -是吗？
- Really? - Really?
要是儿子都发誓了，我们得相信
Well, if our son gives us his word, we've gotta believe him.
说得对
You're right.
麦克，我相信你
I believe you, Mike.
谢谢，我就知道能信任你们
Well, thanks. I knew I could count on you guys.
我为我平时让你们 痛不欲生的行为道歉
I am sorry for every miserable thing I've ever done to make your world a living hell.
对不起，我刚才怀疑你
And I'm sorry I doubted you, Mike...
但站在我的角度 你也能理解这事很难相信
but it's a tough story to believe if you put yourself in my shoes.
妈妈的鞋子可写不下所有答案
Mom's shoes aren't big enough for all the answers.
对了，鞋子的事，谢谢
All right, the shoes. Thanks, Benny.
我忘了最有趣的部分
I forgot to tell you guys the funniest part.
你们一定会喜欢听
You guys are gonna love this.
麦克？
Mike?
-本尼迪克特.阿诺德将军？ -不，本.西弗
- Benedict Arnold. - No, Ben Seaver.
走开
Get away.
吃饭吗？
Want some dinner?
我再也不吃.
No, I am no longer eating the food...
那些认为我撒谎的人的食物
that has been paid for by the people who think I'm a liar.
那些是什么？
Then what are those?
这事要循序渐进嘛
Okay, so I'm easing into it.
你要干什么？
What do you want anyway?
麦克，我不知道会带来这么多麻烦
Mike, I didn't mean to get you in such big trouble.
没关系
It's okay.
我也知道鞋子的事难以接受
I knew the shoes would be too much for them.
已经一整天了
It's been like that all day.
全校的人，连邦纳也是
Everybody at school, even Boner.
去年我还成功骗了他，我是外星人
I mean, last year I actually convinced the man I was an alien.
人们都预想我要作弊
Ben, people are acting like they expect me to cheat.
把我当作是个臭小子
Like I'm that kind of low scuzzball.
我相信你
I believe you.
什么？
What?
不管是真是假，你说什么我都相信你
Whatever you say I believe it, whether it's the truth or not.
告诉你最怪的感觉
Well, I'll tell you something weird.
爸爸妈妈相信我那一刻
That moment when Mom and Dad believed me...
事情好好的
everything was okay.
天哪!我竟然在乎他们对我的看法
My God! I actually care what they think about me.
我也在乎他们对我的看法
I care what they think about me.
但你才9岁，这是正常的
Well, you're nine. That's okay to feel that way at nine.
我15岁了，我应该感到父母是废物
But I'm 15. I'm supposed to think my parents are scum.
你肯定？
Are you sure?
这是众所周知的，电视上也能看到
Yeah, everybody knows that. It's on TV all the time.
我相信你
I believe you.
你在这
There you are.
外面很冷
You're gonna freeze out here.
心中的怒火让我温暖
No, I've got my anger to keep me warm.
我可以分担吗？
Could you share some with me?
杰森，我有话对你说
Jason, I have something to tell you.
其实不想说的，现在麦克出卖了你.
Now I didn't want to tell you, but since you're feeling betrayed by Mike...
你需要一些好消息振奋一下
I figure you'd need some good news.
你不是麦克的父亲
You're not really Mike's father.
你猜我在想什么？
Well, you know what I've been thinking?
麦克能在你面前撒谎.
That when Mike looked you in the eye and lied...
让你质疑你教导孩子诚实的方法
it made you question your whole approach to teaching our kids...
这种方法对不对
the value of truth and honesty.
你疑问通过举例来教导.
And you're wondering if instead of encouraging them by example...
到不如换成用惩罚来教导
a little fear of punishment might have been even more effective.
也许你还记得麦克8岁的时候
And you're probably remembering the time when Mike was eight...
他撒谎没有弄脏新地毯，我要打他
and he lied about finger-painting the new rug, and I wanted to spank him...
你却说服了我应该跟他讲道理
but you convinced me that reasoning with him was better.
这你是怎么做到的？
How do you do that?
这不算什么
Oh, it's not all that amazing.
我看你也知道我在想什么
I bet you know what I'm thinking right now.
你也许在想虽然我们对麦克很失望.
You're probably thinking that no matter how disappointed we both are in Mike...
我们还是很疼他
that we love him dearly.
我们会尽力把他塑造成诚实的人
And that we'll do our best to mold him into an honest man.
若是不成功，也可以让他当政客
And that even if we fail, he can always have a productive life in politics.
麦克，坦白从宽
Mike, Mr. Dewitt will go a lot easier on you, if you just admit what you did.
-我不在乎 -我们在乎
- I don't care. - Well, we do.
你就装作在乎我们的感受好吗？
Couldn't you at least pretend that you care what we think?
没有人相信我
Sure, but nobody'll believe me.
-为什么要相信你？ -因为我没有作弊
- But why should anyone? - Because I didn't cheat.
算了，没关系
Forget it. It doesn't matter.
我们应该相信你初一时.
Well, should we have believed you back in the seventh grade...
你说的成绩单上的“差”是指“差点满分”？
when you tried to tell us that the D on your report card stood for "darn good"?
初二时你骗老师.
And what about in the eighth grade when you told the school...
说你是犹太人，于是多了几天假期？
your name was Seaverman so you could take the Jewish holidays off?
-就说这个星期.. -好吧，好吧
- And, Mike, just this week... - Okay, okay.
有时候.
All right, sometimes...
我是撒谎了
I lie.
但撒谎和“撒谎”是不同的
But there's a big difference between being a liar and being a liar.
你们应该知道我何时说真话
I mean, you guys should know when I'm telling the truth.
你们是怎样的父母？
What kind of parents are you anyway?
失望的父母
Disappointed.
想知道真相？
You wanna know the truth?
我告诉你真相
Okay, I'll tell you the truth.
我是准备作弊 我以为这是唯一的出路
Yeah, I was going to cheat. I figured it was the only way.
于是我熬夜把东西写在鞋底
So I was up half the night copying all that stuff onto my shoes...
这考试不能不过
'cause I had to pass the test.
但不知为何，不仅写在鞋子上 更写进脑袋里了
But somehow it didn't just go on my shoes. It got in my head, too.
我也吓了一跳
It sure blew me away.
当我要看答案时，我不用看也知道了
But when it came time to look for the answers, I didn't have to.
我都知道
I knew them.
麦克，我也想相信你
Well, I'd like to believe you, Mike.
嗯
Yeah.
但你得承认，你并不像那种.
You have to admit you're not exactly the kind of guy who has a reputation...
能记住林肯是第17任总统的人
for knowing things like Abraham Lincoln was the 17th President.
爸，他是第16任总统
Yeah, he was the 16th President, Dad.
-格兰特是第17任 -不，格兰特是第18任
- Yes, Grant was 17th. - No, Grant was the 18th.
约翰逊才是第17任
See, Johnson was 17th.
林肯在1865年4月14日被刺后 他成为了总统
He became President after Lincoln was assassinated on April 14, 1865.
西弗先生，西弗太太，我是得威特老师 谢谢你们能来
Dr. And Mrs. Seaver, I'm Willis Dewitt. Glad you could come.
我们谈正事吧
Why don't we get right down to business?
好的
Absolutely.
麦克考试时并没有作弊
Mike did not cheat on this examination, Mr. Dewitt...
这事可不能含糊
and it's important that we clear that up.
光看脚底下的答案.
And it would have been so easy for him to do...
这也太没意思了吧？
what with all the answers written on the bottom of his shoes.
老师，谢谢你能让麦克重考
I want to thank you, Mr. Dewitt, for letting Mike take this make-up test.
没问题
No problem.
希望他知道意图作弊和作弊 是同等严重的
I think he's learned now that intending to cheat was just as bad as cheating itself.
我前期也是这么说我
That's what my ex-wife said in court.
他要考试呢
He's trying to take a test.
今晚有什么节目？
What's on tonight?
琼.科林系列的第二集
It's the second night of that Joan Collins mini-series.
也许很好看
That might be interesting.
今晚琼要离开教皇，嫁给一个建筑工人
Tonight Joan leaves the Pope to marry a bricklayer.
麦克错过好节目了
Mike'll be sorry he's missing that one.
麦克在哪？整晚没见到他
Where is Mike anyway? I haven't seen him all evening.
他在楼上准备明天的法语考试
Well, he's upstairs studying for his French test tomorrow.
这次他也许相通了
You know, I really think we got through to him this time.
[zeroxia@gmail.com] 2006.04.01